<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Number One</title>
      <link>/post/post-number-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post-number-one/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I suppose this is my &lt;em&gt;hello world&lt;/em&gt; post – I’ve never been good at getting my messages out there (I’m minimally active on social media, etc) but this is part of my attempt to rectify that a little. I have wanted to start a blog for a long time and in fact, I previously started one but failed to keep it going (hopefully this time it’ll be different!). I had called that one ‘Quietly Analysing’ which was mostly inspired from a quote by Ian Hacking in 1936.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The quiet statisticians have changed our world - not by discovering new facts or technical developments but by changing the ways we reason, experiment and form our opinions about it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s still one of my favourite quotes about statistics but I won’t be continuing with that name as this will be more of a personal/professional website for myself. That blog no longer exists so this is effectively a new start for me. I intend to use this website as a place where I can refer others to my academic and analytical work/projects (e.g. at conferences and for current/future employers) but also as a place where I can write up things to aid my own learning and share with others. Occasionally I may write something personal. This point about writing is important as I’ve always felt that I need to get better at writing so hopefully just trying to do this more will help me improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this, I am also hoping to contribute more as a member of the R community – a community that I have always found to be warm, friendly and welcoming. Since I am from Scotland I have to give a particular mention to &lt;a href=&#34;http://edinbr.org&#34;&gt;EdinbR&lt;/a&gt;, who have been doing a great job of promoting R in Scotland (and I have to shamefully admit that I haven’t been able to be a part of as much as I wish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am still fairly new to using web tools so still count myself as a beginner in this area and I’m basically learning as I go. Therefore, I really have to acknowledge some people who have created amazing tools and resources that have helped me immensely in getting this website up and running. I am very grateful to &lt;a href=&#34;https://yihui.name/en&#34;&gt;Yihui Xie&lt;/a&gt; for creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt; (and so many other fantastic tools such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org&#34;&gt;bookdown&lt;/a&gt;) which I am using to create this website; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic&#34;&gt;Hugo Academic template&lt;/a&gt;; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://alison.rbind.io&#34;&gt;Alison Presmanes Hill&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://amber.rbind.io&#34;&gt;Amber Thomas&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://lmyint.github.io&#34;&gt;Leslie Myint&lt;/a&gt; for their useful tips in setting up with blogdown and the Hugo Academic template.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
