<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HCV on Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/tags/hcv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HCV on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alan-y.netlify.com/tags/hcv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing risk bias in prognostic models predicting hepatocellular carcinoma occurrence: impact on clinical decision making</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-risk-bias-hcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-risk-bias-hcc/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this study was to quantify the bias in estimating risk of hepatocellular carcinoma for patients with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population-level estimates of hepatitis C reinfection post scale-up of direct-acting antivirals among people who inject drugs</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_reinf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_reinf/</guid>
      <description>We estimated HCV reinfection rates among PWID in Scotland pre and post-introduction of DAAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance of models to predict hepatocellular carcinoma risk among UK patients with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C infection</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-model/</guid>
      <description>We conducted an external validation of six HCC prediction models for UK patients with cirrhosis HCV virological cure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduction in the population prevalence of HCV viraemia among people who inject drugs associated with scale-up of direct-acting antiviral therapy in community drug services: real world data</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_prev_daa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_prev_daa/</guid>
      <description>We assessed the impact of rapid DAA scale‐up to PWID delivered through community services in the Tayside region of Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population impact of direct-acting antiviral treatment on new presentations of hepatitis C-related decompensated cirrhosis: a national record-linkage study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</guid>
      <description>We examined the impact of the introduction of direct-acting antiviral (DAA) therapies on hepatitis C related decompensated cirrhosis (DC) through analysis of population-based data from Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the population impact of hepatitis C direct acting antiviral treatment as prevention for people who inject drugs (EPIToPe) – a natural experiment (protocol)</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hcv_epitope_protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hcv_epitope_protocol/</guid>
      <description>This is a protocol paper for a natural experiment that looks at the population impact of scaling up hepatitis C treatment with direct acting antiviral treatments as a way to prevent disease transmission and reduce prevalence/incidence among people who inject drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of Novel Psychoactive Substance injecting associated with rapid rise in the population prevalence of hepatitis C virus</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</guid>
      <description>This study provides one of the first epidemiological analyses of the association between NPS injecting and HCV among a population level sample of PWID.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>