<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of Novel Psychoactive Substance injecting associated with rapid rise in the population prevalence of hepatitis C virus</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</guid>
      <description>This study provides one of the first epidemiological analyses of the association between NPS injecting and HCV among a population level sample of PWID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between universal hepatitis B prison vaccination, vaccine uptake and hepatitis B infection among people who inject drugs</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article_hbv_prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/journal-article_hbv_prison/</guid>
      <description>This study examines the impact of the HBV vaccination programme for prisoners in Scotland among people who inject drugs (PWID) in the community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the impact of a temporary class drug order on ethylphenidate-related infections among people who inject drugs in Lothian, Scotland: an interrupted time-series analysis</title>
      <link>/publication/journal-article_nps_tcdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/journal-article_nps_tcdo/</guid>
      <description>In April 2015, the UK government enacted a temporary class drug order (TCDO) on ethylphenidate in response to reported harms associated with its use, in particular an outbreak of infections among people who inject drugs (PWID) in Lothian, Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B infection in Scotland: 2015</title>
      <link>/publication/report-hbv2015_hps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/report-hbv2015_hps/</guid>
      <description>This report looks at the epidemiology of hepatitis B in Scotland up to 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Applications in the Analysis of Vaccine Preventable Diseases</title>
      <link>/publication/phd-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/phd-thesis/</guid>
      <description>This thesis applies and develops statistical methods to studies of vaccine-preventable disease outbreaks in Scotland and aims to aid in the detection and management of outbreaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>I am a research fellow at Glasgow Caledonian University and an analyst at Health Protection Scotland. My main research interests relate to the epidemiology and prevention of blood borne viruses as well as the evaluation of policies related to this field. I provide analytical and statistical support for a broad range of blood borne viruses including hepatitis B, hepatitis C and HIV. I am also a supporter for the widespread adoption of open-source statistical software within the public sector in Scotland, particularly for the use of R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>