<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 on Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication_types/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A transient positive association between direct-acting antiviral therapy for hepatitis C infection and drug-related hospitalization among people who inject drugs: Self-controlled case-series analysis of national data</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-transient_daa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-transient_daa/</guid>
      <description>We investigated associations between outcomes and DAA treatment by comparing post-treatment to baseline periods using a within-subjects design</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National increase in the community supply of take-home naloxone associated with a mass media campaign in Scotland: a segmented time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_naloxone_media/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_naloxone_media/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this study was to assess the effect of the &amp;lsquo;How to save a life&amp;rsquo; campaign on the supply of take-home naloxone</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality rates among patients successfully treated for hepatitis C in the era of interferon-free antivirals: population based cohort study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-mortality_treated_hcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-mortality_treated_hcv/</guid>
      <description>This study compared mortality rates for patients treated for hepatitis C in the era of direct acting antivirals with the general population</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mortality among individuals prescribed opioid-agonist therapy in Scotland, UK, 2011-20: a national retrospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-oat_mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-oat_mortality/</guid>
      <description>We assessed the extent to which opioid-agonist therapy is protective against drug-related mortality in Scotland</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Predicted Probability of Hepatocellular Carcinoma in Patients With Cirrhosis With the General Population: An Opportunity to Improve Risk Communication?</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-comparing_hcc_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-comparing_hcc_prob/</guid>
      <description>We compared the predicted hepatocellular carcinoma probability for individuals with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C with the general population</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examining the impact of the first wave of COVID-19 and associated control measures on interventions to prevent blood-borne viruses among people who inject drugs in Scotland: an interrupted time series study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-covid_bbv_its/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-covid_bbv_its/</guid>
      <description>We examined the impact of the first wave of COVID-19 in Scotland on drug and BBV services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declining incidence of hepatitis C related hepatocellular carcinoma in the era of interferon-free therapies: A population-based cohort study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-decline/</guid>
      <description>This study explores the impact of interferon-free therapies on hepatitis C virus related hepatocellular carcinoma at a population level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing risk bias in prognostic models predicting hepatocellular carcinoma occurrence: impact on clinical decision making</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-risk-bias-hcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-risk-bias-hcc/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this study was to quantify the bias in estimating risk of hepatocellular carcinoma for patients with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population-level estimates of hepatitis C reinfection post scale-up of direct-acting antivirals among people who inject drugs</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_reinf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_reinf/</guid>
      <description>We estimated HCV reinfection rates among PWID in Scotland pre and post-introduction of DAAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance of models to predict hepatocellular carcinoma risk among UK patients with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C infection</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-model/</guid>
      <description>We conducted an external validation of six HCC prediction models for UK patients with cirrhosis HCV virological cure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A systematic review and meta-analysis of the prevalence of take-home naloxone (THN) ownership and carriage</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_thn_meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_thn_meta/</guid>
      <description>This study aimed to assess the prevalence of ownership and carriage of Take-Home Naloxone internationally among people who use drugs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduction in the population prevalence of HCV viraemia among people who inject drugs associated with scale-up of direct-acting antiviral therapy in community drug services: real world data</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_prev_daa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_prev_daa/</guid>
      <description>We assessed the impact of rapid DAA scale‐up to PWID delivered through community services in the Tayside region of Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of a national HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis service is associated with changes in characteristics of people with newly diagnosed HIV: a retrospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-prep-char/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-prep-char/</guid>
      <description>The study reviewed characteristics of individuals newly diagnosed with HIV following implementation of a national PrEP programme to inform future delivery and broader HIV prevention strategies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population-level effectiveness of a national HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis programme in MSM</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-prep-incidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-prep-incidence/</guid>
      <description>The study evaluated Scotland&amp;rsquo;s national HIV PrEP programme in relation to PrEP uptake and associated population-level impact on HIV incidence among MSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population impact of direct-acting antiviral treatment on new presentations of hepatitis C-related decompensated cirrhosis: a national record-linkage study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</guid>
      <description>We examined the impact of the introduction of direct-acting antiviral (DAA) therapies on hepatitis C related decompensated cirrhosis (DC) through analysis of population-based data from Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the population impact of hepatitis C direct acting antiviral treatment as prevention for people who inject drugs (EPIToPe) – a natural experiment (protocol)</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hcv_epitope_protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hcv_epitope_protocol/</guid>
      <description>This is a protocol paper for a natural experiment that looks at the population impact of scaling up hepatitis C treatment with direct acting antiviral treatments as a way to prevent disease transmission and reduce prevalence/incidence among people who inject drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of Novel Psychoactive Substance injecting associated with rapid rise in the population prevalence of hepatitis C virus</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</guid>
      <description>This study provides one of the first epidemiological analyses of the association between NPS injecting and HCV among a population level sample of PWID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between universal hepatitis B prison vaccination, vaccine uptake and hepatitis B infection among people who inject drugs</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hbv_prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hbv_prison/</guid>
      <description>This study examines the impact of the HBV vaccination programme for prisoners in Scotland among people who inject drugs (PWID) in the community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the impact of a temporary class drug order on ethylphenidate-related infections among people who inject drugs in Lothian, Scotland: an interrupted time-series analysis</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_tcdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_tcdo/</guid>
      <description>In April 2015, the UK government enacted a temporary class drug order (TCDO) on ethylphenidate in response to reported harms associated with its use, in particular an outbreak of infections among people who inject drugs (PWID) in Lothian, Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>