<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 on Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication_types/2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Population-level effectiveness of a national HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis programme in MSM</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-prep-incidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-prep-incidence/</guid>
      <description>The study evaluated Scotland&amp;rsquo;s national HIV PrEP programme in relation to PrEP uptake and associated population-level impact on HIV incidence among MSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population impact of direct-acting antiviral treatment on new presentations of hepatitis C-related decompensated cirrhosis: a national record-linkage study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</guid>
      <description>We examined the impact of the introduction of direct-acting antiviral (DAA) therapies on hepatitis C related decompensated cirrhosis (DC) through analysis of population-based data from Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the population impact of hepatitis C direct acting antiviral treatment as prevention for people who inject drugs (EPIToPe) – a natural experiment (protocol)</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hcv_epitope_protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hcv_epitope_protocol/</guid>
      <description>This is a protocol paper for a natural experiment that looks at the population impact of scaling up hepatitis C treatment with direct acting antiviral treatments as a way to prevent disease transmission and reduce prevalence/incidence among people who inject drugs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergence of Novel Psychoactive Substance injecting associated with rapid rise in the population prevalence of hepatitis C virus</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_hcv/</guid>
      <description>This study provides one of the first epidemiological analyses of the association between NPS injecting and HCV among a population level sample of PWID.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between universal hepatitis B prison vaccination, vaccine uptake and hepatitis B infection among people who inject drugs</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hbv_prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_hbv_prison/</guid>
      <description>This study examines the impact of the HBV vaccination programme for prisoners in Scotland among people who inject drugs (PWID) in the community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the impact of a temporary class drug order on ethylphenidate-related infections among people who inject drugs in Lothian, Scotland: an interrupted time-series analysis</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_tcdo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article_nps_tcdo/</guid>
      <description>In April 2015, the UK government enacted a temporary class drug order (TCDO) on ethylphenidate in response to reported harms associated with its use, in particular an outbreak of infections among people who inject drugs (PWID) in Lothian, Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>