<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking dbplyr for CKAN</title>
      <link>/post/ckan-dbplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ckan-dbplyr/</guid>
      <description>AimCreate a dummy databaseTest dbplyr’s SQL translationModify dbplyr’s SQL translationTesting the dbplyr hackConcluding notesAt the end of my first post on CKAN discussing how to use the CKAN API to extract data from the NHS open data platform directly into R, I talked about how it would be neat to write some wrapper functions to make this process a little simpler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Open Data into R from CKAN</title>
      <link>/post/ckan-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ckan-api/</guid>
      <description>PreambleOpen Data in ScotlandQuerying CKANQuerying with Custom JSONQuerying with SQLConclusions and Further IdeasPreambleI’ve got lots of rough pieces of R code written as I’ve been exploring/testing various things in the past. A lot of this is currently stored in a pretty disorganised fashion so I thought it would be a good idea to start writing some of these up into blog posts – at the very least, this should make it easier for me to find things later!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glasgow R User Group</title>
      <link>/post/glasgow-r-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/glasgow-r-user-group/</guid>
      <description>I am very excited to hear that there are attempts to create a brand new R user group in Glasgow! I had just talked in Post Number One about my guilt at not having been able to attend EdinbR as often as I wished but it should be much easier for me to find time to attend a group based in Glasgow. If you are based in (or near) Glasgow and would like to join the R community, this sounds like the place to be – I hope this idea takes off!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Training Resources and Tips</title>
      <link>/project/r-resources-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/r-resources-tips/</guid>
      <description>A short list of resources and tips to help with learning some R basics, with particular focus on the tidyverse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>phiproject</title>
      <link>/project/phiproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/phiproject/</guid>
      <description>An RStudio project template incorporating some best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>objectremover RStudio Addin</title>
      <link>/project/objectremover/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/objectremover/</guid>
      <description>An RStudio addin to assist with removing objects from the global environment. Features include removing objects according to name patterns and object type.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>