<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cirrhosis on Alan Yeung</title>
    <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/tags/cirrhosis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cirrhosis on Alan Yeung</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alan Yeung</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alan-y.netlify.com/tags/cirrhosis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Predicted Probability of Hepatocellular Carcinoma in Patients With Cirrhosis With the General Population: An Opportunity to Improve Risk Communication?</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-comparing_hcc_prob/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-comparing_hcc_prob/</guid>
      <description>We compared the predicted hepatocellular carcinoma probability for individuals with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C with the general population</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declining incidence of hepatitis C related hepatocellular carcinoma in the era of interferon-free therapies: A population-based cohort study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-decline/</guid>
      <description>This study explores the impact of interferon-free therapies on hepatitis C virus related hepatocellular carcinoma at a population level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing risk bias in prognostic models predicting hepatocellular carcinoma occurrence: impact on clinical decision making</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-risk-bias-hcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-risk-bias-hcc/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this study was to quantify the bias in estimating risk of hepatocellular carcinoma for patients with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance of models to predict hepatocellular carcinoma risk among UK patients with cirrhosis and cured hepatitis C infection</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcc-model/</guid>
      <description>We conducted an external validation of six HCC prediction models for UK patients with cirrhosis HCV virological cure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population impact of direct-acting antiviral treatment on new presentations of hepatitis C-related decompensated cirrhosis: a national record-linkage study</title>
      <link>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alan-y.netlify.com/publication/journal-article-hcv_daa_dc/</guid>
      <description>We examined the impact of the introduction of direct-acting antiviral (DAA) therapies on hepatitis C related decompensated cirrhosis (DC) through analysis of population-based data from Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>